Then see, you program my mutation, so
it's unsafe in the sense that any
function can mutate any variables any
time. It does a lot you you pass
pointers around a lot and functions
mutate the memory pointed to by those
pointers. And moreover, typically they
can mutate it anywhere. There's no array
bounds checks or anything. So, it's kind
of like super unsafe and in fact and
this is demonstrated by the fact can you
imagine that like all of these exploits
that we get every day, right? Um
that you know, MSRC is discovering in
huge numbers, but but we've had you know
Why is the internet so insecure?
Primarily because all of our software
infrastructure is written in unsafe
languages. If we I mean
if we'd written all of our,
you know, internet software and
operating systems in Haskell or maybe in
OCaml or ML
99% of all these exploits would be
removed by construction.
Like it's like we've built a boat out of
paperclips and we're surprised that it's
leaky. I mean, you shouldn't build boats
out of paperclips, right? Because they
have a holes in them. You should build
it out of a secure substance. Like but
then it's too late. So, we spend
incredible amounts of human ingenuity
and effort patching the holes in our
boat built of paperclips. It's tragic.
It's tragic how much effort and
ingenuity and money has been lost and
waste of resources just because we wrote
our
you know computational infrastructure
for the world in an insecure language.
That's what I mean by unsafe. How many
exploits are based on buffer overruns?
Or you know, pointer manipulation that's
gone wrong. If you couldn't have a
buffer overrun, you couldn't do pointer
manipulation that go wrong. Those those
exploits just wouldn't exist.
>> What about more modern versions of those
lower-level languages?
>> Oh, much much better. Much much much
better, right? If we rewrote all of our
software infrastructure in Rust
things would be way way
I I'm not actually even sure whether
Rust has array bounds checks built in,
but suppose it but it must have the
ability to
promise that you're not and actually out
of bounds. I don't quite know quite know
how, but if you compile all your code
with that switched on,
you're a way better situation. Way
better.
So, yes, this is not just functional
programming, but you did ask about why I
thought C was an insecure, unsafe
language.